Ruler of monsters, and all
those who are loyal to him,
（トレイニー）
魔物を統べる者
および その従者たる皆様
forgive me for this unannounced visit.
突然の訪問 相すみません
（トレイニー）
私は
ドライアドのトレイニーと申します
I am Treyni, a Dryad.
どうぞ お見知りおきください
It is a pleasure to meet you.
Rimuru Tempest, ruler of
monsters, I would like you
リムル＝テンペスト
魔物を統べる者よ
あなたに…
to defeat the Orc Lord.
オークロードの討伐を
依頼したいのです
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Episode 12: The Gears Spin Out of Control
Defeat the Orc Lord?
（リムル）オークロードの討伐…
ええっと… 俺がですか？
Um... You're asking me?
ええ そうです
Yes, that's right.
That's quite a selfish request from
someone who just appeared out of nowhere,
（ベニマル）いきなり現れて…
（リムル）ん？
（ベニマル）
随分 身勝手な物言いじゃないか
ドライアドのトレイニーとやら
Treyni the Dryad.
なぜ この町へ来た？
Why have you come here?
There are races far stronger than Goblins.
ゴブリンよりも強い種族は
いるだろう
Yes, that is true.
そうですわね
If the Ogres' homeland had
been at full strength,
オーガの里が健在でしたら
そちらに出向いていたでしょう
perhaps I would have gone there.
Though, even if I had done that,
まあ そうであったとしても
I still could not have ignored
this individual's existence.
この方の存在を無視することは
できないのですけれど
Were our settlement to be
attacked by the Orc Lord,
（トレイニー）
我々の集落が
オークロードに狙われれば
ドライアドだけでは
抵抗できませんの
the Dryads could not hope
to fight them alone.
ですから こうして
強き者に助力を願いに来たのです
This is why I have come to request
assistance from someone strong.
The idea that the Orc Lord even existed
was still just a theory to us...
オークロードがいるってこと自体
俺たちの中では
仮説だったんだけど…
The Dryads have knowledge of essentially
everything that happens in this forest.
（トレイニー）
ドライアドは
この森で起きたことならば
大抵 把握しておりますの
いますよ？　オークロード
The Orc Lord does exist.
If a Dryad acknowledges it...
（リグルド）
ドライアド様が お認めに
Then it must be true.
（カイジン）
ならば 本当に…
返事は少し待ってくれ
Give me some time to answer.
I will back up the Kijin,
鬼人(きじん)たちの援護はするが
but I don't want to go poking at
a hornet's nest for no reason.
率先して
藪(やぶ)をつつくつもりはないんだ
Let me take stock of the information
we have before I answer.
情報を整理してから答えさせてくれ
こう見えても ここの主(あるじ)なんでな
Despite how I look, I'm the
leader here, after all.
Let's continue the conference.
（リムル）会議を続けるぞ
Anyone have any ideas what
the Orcs might be after?
オークたちの目的について
何か意見のある者はいるか？
One thing does come to mind...
（シュナ）
思い当たることが… １つあります
Okay.
（シュナ）ソウエイ
Souei, did you investigate our village?
私たちの里 調査してきましたか？
（ソウエイ）はい
Yes.
その様子では やはり…
なかったのですね
Judging by your reaction,
I assume you found none?
Correct.
（ソウエイ）はい
（リムル）ん？
同胞のものも オークのものも
Not a single one belonging to
either our brethren or the Orcs.
ただのひとつも
何が？
Not one what?
死体です
Corpse.
20万もの大軍が食えるだけの食料を
We didn't understand how they
were getting the supplies
to keep an army of 200,000 fed.
どうやって賄っているのか
疑問だったが…
Are you saying...
それって まさか…
The unique skill...
（トレイニー）ユニークスキル
Starved
“飢餓者(ウエルモノ)”
Starved.
Starved?
（リムル）ウエルモノ…
It's a skill that the Orc Lord,
（トレイニー）
世に混乱をもたらす災厄の魔物
a calamity that brings chaos
to the world, is born with.
オークロードが生まれながらにして
保有しているスキルで
Its influence reaches all
those who serve under him,
オークロードの支配下にある
全てのものに影響を及ぼし
Trample all! Trample all! Trample all!
making them devour everything
in sight, like locusts.
イナゴのように
周囲の者を食べ尽くす
At the same time, they consume the
victim's strength and abilities,
食らった相手の力や能力までも
取り込み
making them their own sustenance.
自分の糧とするのですわ
The strength of this comrade
we eat is now ours!
（オークたち）
食べた仲間の力を我が物に！
The strength of this prey we eat is now ours!
食べた獲物の力を我が物に！
It's quite similar to your Predator skill.
（トレイニー）
あなた様の“捕食者”と
似ていますわね
In return for obtaining Starved,
ウエルモノの代償は
満たされることのない飢餓感
they feel constant, insatiable hunger.
The Orcs move forward for no other purpose
オークたちは
果てしない飢えを満たし
than to sate their endless
hunger and gain more power.
力を得るためだけに進むのですわ
That is their king's only wish.
ただそれだけが
彼らの王の望みゆえに…
So the Orcs' goal isn't to wipe out
（リムル）オークの狙いは
オーガやリザードマンといった
森の上位種族を滅ぼすことではなく
the superior forest races,
the Ogres and Lizardmen,
but to steal their powers?
その力を奪うこと… か？
Well, if that's the case,
さて… となるとだな
うちも安全とは言い難いな
I can't say we're in the clear.
We have Tempest Wolves,
Kijin, and Hobgoblins.
テンペストウルフに鬼人
ホブゴブリン
Flavors aside, they're all meals with
powers that the Orcs would kill for.
味はともかく オークたちの
欲しがりそうな力を持った
餌だらけだ
いちばん
ヤツらの食いつきそうな餌を
Aren't you forgetting the one meal
that would attract them the most?
忘れてやいませんか？
Huh?
We have the strongest slime here, remember?
（ベニマル）
いるでしょ 最強のスライムが
Where?
どこに？
Huh?
In addition, we have confirmed
that a certain majin
（トレイニー）
それに
オークロード誕生のきっかけとして
is behind the Orc Lord's appearance.
魔人の存在を確認しております
あなた様は放っておけない相手かと
思いますけど
I believe it is someone you
won't want to overlook.
A majin?
魔人か…
It is a subordinate of
a Demon Lord, after all.
いずれかの魔王の手の者ですからね
They have knowledge of everything
that happens in the forest, huh?
（リムル）
“森で起きたことは
大抵 把握している”か…
This lady's shrewd.
食えない おねえちゃんだ
Honored Rimuru Tempest.
（トレイニー）
リムル＝テンペスト様
改めて
オークロードの討伐を依頼します
I once again request that
you defeat the Orc Lord.
暴風竜ヴェルドラの加護を受け
牙狼族(がろうぞく)を下し
As the one who received the
Storm Dragon Veldora's protection,
subjugated the Direwolves,
and became the patron of the Kijin,
鬼人を庇護(ひご)する あなた様なら
you are surely more than
a match for the Orc Lord.
オークロードに
遅れを取ることはないでしょう
（リムル）
う〜ん… 大賢者(だいけんじゃ) どう思う？
What do you think, Great Sage?
Can I trust her?
信用していいのか？
Caretakers of the Forest
The Dryads are the caretakers
of the Great Forest of Jura.
（大賢者）
ドライアドは
ジュラの大森林の管理者
Caretakers of the Forest
They are said to be the ones who
pass divine justice on villains
不届きな者
森に対し害意を持つ者に対し
They pass divine justice
on villains and any who would
harm the forest
and any who would harm the forest.
天罰を下す存在ともいわれています
Divine Justice
Divine justice, huh?
（リムル）
天罰か…
But there are 200,000 of them.
でもなあ 20万だぞ
Of course he will!
（シオン）当然です！
（リムル）えっ？
That Orc Lord is no match for Great Rimuru!
（シオン）
リムル様ならば オークロードなど
敵ではありません！
Oh, you agree with me, then?
まあ！　やはり そうですよね
Yes!
Are you kidding me?! Did she really just...
（リムル）
ウソ〜ん！　この娘(こ) 勝手に…
Fine. I'll accept this request
to beat the Demon Lord.
（リムル）
分かったよ
オークロードの件は俺が引き受ける
You're all in this with me.
みんなも そのつもりでいてくれ
Of course, Great Rimuru!
はい！　もちろんです リムル様！
That was our plan all along.
どうせ最初から そのつもりだ
We believe in you, and we're
with you. That's all we need.
俺たちは旦那を信じて
ついていくだけさ
Exactly!
（リグルド）そのとおりですぞ！
Let's show them how strong we are!
我らの力を
見せつけてやりましょう！
Yeah!
（一同）おう！
I acted all cool about it,
but what if we lose?
（リムル）
な〜んて格好つけて
負けたらどうしよう
If we're taking on an army of 200,000 Orcs,
（リムル）
オーク20万の軍勢を
相手取るとなると
I feel like we should consider
an alliance with the Lizardmen,
リザードマンとの同盟を
前向きに検討したいところだが…
but given the guy they
had representing them...
使者がアレなんだよな〜
（ガビル）我が名は…
I am Gabiru!
ガビル！
The Guy
（リムル）
ハア… 話が通じるヤツと
交渉したいところだが
I'd really like to talk to someone
who'll actually listen...
Great Rimuru.
（ソウエイ）リムル様
（リムル）ん？
リザードマンの首領に 直接
話をつけてもよろしいですか？
Would you mind if I spoke personally
with the chieftain of the Lizardmen?
Souei? You can do that?
（リムル）
ソウエイ… できるのか？
はい
Yes.
Oh, my God, he's so confident!
What a dreamboat!
（リムル）
なに この自信？　やだ イケメン！
（リムル）あっ よ… よし！
O-Okay, then.
We'll join forces with the
Lizardmen and attack the Orcs.
では リザードマンと合流し
オークをたたく！
Yes, sir!
The battle will probably take place in the
marshlands inhabited by the Lizardmen.
（リムル）
決戦は リザードマンの
支配領域である湿地帯になるだろう
The Lizardmen's cooperation will
be essential for this to work.
これはリザードマンとの共同戦線が
前提条件だ
I'm counting on you, Souei.
頼んだぞ ソウエイ
お任せを
It shall be done.
I hope their chieftain isn't
an idiot like Gabiru...
（リムル）
首領がアホじゃないといいけど…
ガビルみたいな
Sir Gabiru!
（部下）ガビル様〜！
（ガビル）ぐわあ〜！
（部下の泣き声）
（部下）起きたかよ
You're awake now?
Sir Gabiru...
Wh-Where are we?
こ… ここは？
Thank goodness...
（部下）
よかったよ〜 ホント
ううっ…
Th-That's right! I was...
そっ そうだ！
我が輩は…
defeated by that boy with the dopey face!
あの ふざけた顔の男に！
They clearly tricked us.
うぬ… すっかり だまされたわ
What do you mean?
ど… どういうこと？
It's simple.
（ガビル）簡単なことよ
That boy who beat me
我が輩を制した あの者こそ…
あの村の本当の主に違いない！
is obviously the real master of that village!
（部下たち）なんと！
Really?!
（部下１）
あれが？
That kid?
He must be, or Sir Gabiru wouldn't have lost!
（部下２）
そうじゃないと
ガビル様 負けたりしないよ
（部下３）しかり
Indeed.
What a dirty trick, lowering
Sir Gabiru's guard with such lies!
（部下２）
汚い！　だましてガビル様の油断を
誘うだなんて
（部下３）卑怯(ひきょう)なり！
Cowards!
（部下１）ふざけんな！
How dare they?!
Now, calm down.
（ガビル）まあ 落ち着け
Such is the wisdom of the weak.
弱者なりの知恵というやつだろう
器の大きさ 山のごとし！
What a great man you are!
Great as a mountain!
That's our Sir Gabiru!
さすが ガビル様！
（拍手）
Yeah! Our next chieftain!
いよっ 次期首領！
You're the best, Gabiru!
（ラプラス）
いや〜 かっこええなあ ガビルはん
いやいや
我が輩など それほどでも…
Oh, no, I'm really not so—
って だっ… な？
Wait, who?! Wha?!
最初からいたよ この人
He's been here this whole time.
You're just as great as I've heard!
（ラプラス）
聞いたとおり えらい男前やないか
My name is Laplace.
わいはラプラスという者(もん)です
Laplace?
（ガビル）ラプラス？
I've come as a servant of
Lord Gelmud to give you a warning.
（ラプラス）
ゲルミュッド様の使いで
あんたに警告をしに来たんや
Oh! Lord Gelmud!
おお！　ゲルミュッド様の
Who's Lord Gelmud?
ゲルミュッド様って？
He's the man who gave Sir Gabiru his name.
ガビル様に
名を授けてくださったというお方だ
Thank you for taking the trouble to come!
ご足労を おかけしたな
So, what is Lord Gelmud's warning?
して ゲルミュッド様の警告とは？
Well, we have quite the
situation on our hands!
（ラプラス）
これがまた
えらいことになっとるんですわ！
It seems that army of Orcs
今回のオークの軍勢…
really is being led by an Orc Lord.
どうやら本当にオークロードが
率いてるらしいでっせ
（どよめき）
（部下たち）オークロード？
An Orc Lord?!
The Lizardman chieftain is a capable man,
（ラプラス）
リザードマンの首領は
できた お人やけど
but he's getting up there in years, you know!
もう かなりのお年やし
正直なとこ… お父上には
荷が重いんとちゃいます？
Frankly speaking...
Don't you think this is a bit
much for Daddy to handle?
オーク軍撃退の後に 首領の座を
受け継ごうと思っていたが
I had planned to take over as chieftain
after we had fought off the Orcs,
but it seems that would be too late!
それでは間に合わんようだな！
Yep, exactly!
ラプラス殿
Laplace, forgive my leaving
so abruptly, but we—
挨拶もそこそこだが
我が輩たちは…
（ラプラス）
ええって ええって
湿地帯に戻りはるんやろ？
Oh, it's fine, it's fine!
You're going back to the marshlands, right?
You should hurry!
はよ行ったほうがええで
Thank you.
かたじけない
出発するぞ〜！
Let us go!
Yeah!
Do the best you can, Gabiru.
（ラプラス）
せいぜい頑張りや
ガビルはん
Trample all! Trample all! Trample all!
（オークたち）
蹂躙(じゅうりん)せよ！　蹂躙せよ！
蹂躙せよ！　蹂躙せよ！
蹂躙せよ！　蹂躙せよ…
Chieftain, what shall we do?
（ガビルの妹）
首領 いかがいたしましょう？
オーク軍が迫っておりますが…
The Orc army is approaching.
What can we do but remain here?
（首領）籠城するしかあるまい
We have no means to fight
an army of 200,000 Orcs.
20万のオークを相手に
戦うすべはない
Yes, sir.
Chieftain!
（伝令）首領〜！
Chieftain! We have an intruder!
首領！　侵入者です！
He demands an audience with you!
首領に会わせろと！
会おう　連れてまいれ
Very well. Bring him to me.
Chieftain, is this not dangerous?
首領 危険では…
そなたも感じるか？
このオーラ
You can feel this aura, as well?
Yes. This is no simple intruder.
（ガビルの妹）
ええ ただ者ではありません
これは…
With this one...
even a hundred of the strongest
Lizardmen would stand no chance.
リザードマンの精鋭100体で
かかったとしても…
Forgive me, but my hands are
rather tied at the moment.
失礼 今 取り込んでおりましてな
おもてなしもできませぬ
I cannot spare any hospitality.
No need to trouble yourself.
（ソウエイ）気遣いは無用だ
I am only a messenger, here to convey
to you the words of my master.
俺は単なる使者
我が主の言葉を
伝えに来ただけなのでな
And what is your message?
（首領）して 用件は？
My master desires an alliance
with the Lizardmen.
（ソウエイ）
我が主は
リザードマンとの同盟を望んでいる
An alliance?
（首領）同盟？
But I have no knowledge of your master.
はて… そなたの主を
わしは知らんのだがね
My master is the great Rimuru Tempest.
我が主は リムル＝テンペスト様だ
ドライアドより じかに要請を受け
オーク軍の討伐を確約されている
Upon receiving a personal
request from the Dryads,
he has sworn to defeat
the approaching Orc army.
A personal request from the
caretakers of the forest?
（首領）
森の管理者が… 直接？
オーク軍を率いているのは
オークロードだという
She informed us that the Orc
army is led by an Orc Lord.
An Orc Lord?!
オークロード？
Keep in mind what that means
as you consider our proposal.
（ソウエイ）
この意味を踏まえて
よく検討してほしい
フンッ リムルだと？
聞いたこともない！
Rimuru, you say? Never heard of him!
He probably just came crying to
us because he fears the Orc Lord!
どうせ そいつも
オークロードを恐れて
我らに泣きついてきたんだろう？
If he would just ask for our help...
素直に
助けてくれと言えばいいものを…
Enough.
（首領）やめろ！
（伝令）え？
口を塞ぐのだ
Hold your tongue.
Ch-Chieftain! Such complacency
will lead others to belittle—
しゅっ 首領！
そのような態度ではナメられ…
Wh-What is this?
こっ これは…
Hold.
待て　同族の非礼をわびよう
I apologize for my comrade's rudeness.
Would you please forgive him?
許してやってもらえないかな
これは対等の申し出なのだろう？
This offer does benefit both
of us equally, does it not?
ぐはっ！
Forgive me.
（ソウエイ）
失礼 脅すつもりはなかったが
It was not my intent to threaten him,
主を愚弄されるのは好まぬ
but I will not stand for
such mockery of my master.
Strong words...
（首領）
よく言う…
Had I not stopped him, he would have
taken his head in a heartbeat.
止めねば迷わず
首を はねただろうに
Judging by your aura, you appear
to be an Ogre from the southwest.
（首領）
見たところ そなたのオーラは
南西に暮らすオーガであろう
Not anymore.
今は違う
My master granted me the name
"Souei," and I became a Kijin.
主より ソウエイの名を賜った折
鬼人となった
Kijin?
鬼人？
The superior race born only
rarely from among the Ogres?
オーガの中から
稀(まれ)に生まれるという上位種族…
If that is true, it would
mean that your master
（首領）
ならば そなたに名を与えた主とは
is of an even more superior
race than the Kijin...
それ以上の存在… というわけか
An offer to enter an alliance
（首領）
オークロードの出現…
immediately after the
appearance of the Orc Lord...
この局面において
強者(きょうしゃ)からの同盟の申し出
I have no reason to refuse.
断る理由はないな　だが…
However...
ソウエイとやら １つ条件がある
Souei, was it? I have one condition.
What is it?
（ソウエイ）聞こう
I wish to meet your master, Rimuru Tempest.
そなたの主
リムル＝テンペストと会いたい
Very well.
（ソウエイ）分かった
Then we will make preparations
では 我々は準備を整え
７日後に こちらに合流する
and meet you here in seven days.
You will have an audience with him then.
そのとき
お目通りしていただくとしよう
（首領）うむ
それまでは 決して先走って
戦を仕掛けることのないよう
Ensure that you do not
wage battle before then.
（首領）承知した
Understood.
Then I will go.
では
Chieftain!
（ガビルの妹）首領！
（首領）
ハア…
どうにか光明(こうみょう)が見えたようだ
I feel as if I've seen the light of hope.
皆を集めろ
Gather everyone together.
The Orc army has already drawn
near to this underground cave.
（首領）オーク軍は既に
この地下大洞窟のそばまで
迫ってきている
But there is nothing to fear.
だが 恐れることはない
In seven days,
powerful reinforcements will join us.
７日後には強力な援軍が見込める
Until then, we will remain here and
conserve our strength for battle.
それまで我々は籠城し
戦力を温存するのだ
Do not, for a moment,
think of making the first strike.
間違っても
攻撃に打って出ようなどと思うな
Any who die in battle will be eaten by
the enemy and become their strength!
戦死すれば餌になり
ヤツらの力が増すと思え
That is what it means to fight the Orc Lord.
それが オークロードを相手に戦う
ということだ
援軍と合流した後 反撃に転じる
Once our reinforcements join us,
we will launch a counterattack.
そのときまで耐えるのだ
Resist fighting until then!
誰一人 死ぬことは許さん！
I will not tolerate a
single death among my men!
Four Days Later
All right! Surround him!
（戦士Ａ）
よし！　回り込め！
これが本当にオークなのか？
Is this really an Orc?
まるで
オーガとでも戦っている気分だ
I feel like I just fought an Ogre...
It's chilling to think that there
are 200,000 of these guys.
（戦士Ｂ）
ゾッとするな…
こんなヤツらが20万もいるだなんて
That must be the power of the Orc Lord.
（戦士Ｃ）
それが
オークロードの能力なんだろう
Can we defend this place for three more days?
あと３日も守り通せるだろうか…
If all we do is defend,
we'll exhaust our strength!
（ガビル）
守ってばかりでは疲弊するだけだ
おおっ あなたは！
You're...
Father!
（ガビル）親父(おやじ)殿！
Ah, you've returned.
（首領）おお 戻ったか
Well?
して ゴブリンからの協力は
取り付けることができたのか？
Did you succeed in recruiting
the Goblins to assist us?
Yes, sir!
They number 7,000 in total.
その総数７千匹
待機させております
They are standing by.
うむ
（ガビル）しかし…
But...
オーク相手に籠城とは
どういうつもりなのです？
Why must we remain here in
the face of an Orc attack?
This is not how the proud
Lizardman race fights.
とても誇り高き
リザードマンの戦い方とは
思えませんな
お前がいない間に
同盟の申し出があったのだ
While you were away, we were
approached with an offer of alliance.
その者たちと合流するまでは
防衛に徹するのが最善だ
Until they join us, our best
option is to focus on defense.
You've aged, Father.
老いたな… 親父
What?
なに？
Utilizing these natural labyrinths may
be a wise strategy against a large army.
天然の迷路を利用し
大軍と戦うのは
良い策かもしれん
However, it divides our forces
between too many separate corridors,
だが
それでは あまたある通路に
戦力を分散させ過ぎて
preventing us from meeting the
enemy with our full strength!
戦力の集中による
迎撃ができぬ！
G-Gabiru, what is the meaning of this?
ガ… ガビル殿
これは 一体 どういう…
Be calm, captain of the guard.
（ガビル）
落ち着け！　親衛隊長
危害を加えるつもりはない
I have no intention of harming you.
But...
しかし… うっ！
I will apologize later for
resorting to violence.
（ガビル）
手荒な手段になってしまったことは
あとでわびる
You may feel uncomfortable while restrained,
窮屈な思いをさせるが
but bear with it until I defeat the Orc Lord.
我が輩がオークロードを討つまで
辛抱してくれ！
Son! I will not allow you to do this!
息子よ！　勝手なマネは許さんぞ！
Gabiru... no, Brother!
（ガビルの妹）
ガビル殿… いえ 兄上！
目を覚ましてください！
Please, come to your senses!
Unhand me! Unhand me, I said!
（首領）
ええい 放せ！　放さんか！
放すのだ！　勝手なマネは許さん！
Unhand me at once! I will not stand for this!
ガビル様 これを…
Sir Gabiru, here.
親父殿の…
That's my father's...
Th-This power...
こっ この力…
Vortex Spear, you acknowledge
me as your master now?
ボルテクススピアよ
我が輩を主と認めてくれるのか！
各部族長の掌握が完了したぜ
We've seized the leaders of each clan.
There were a lot of young ones who didn't
agree with this defensive battle.
若い連中には
この防衛戦に疑問を抱いていた者も
多かったからな
そうか
I see.
We're all behind you.
（部下）
みんな あんたについていく
頼むぜ ガビル様
We're counting on you, Sir Gabiru.
Of course.
いいとも
I will show you how a true Lizardman fights!
我が輩がリザードマンの
真の戦い方を見せてやろうぞ
The time has come!
時が来たのだ！
Gabiru! Gabiru! Gabiru!
ガビル！　ガビル！　ガビル…
Trample all! Trample all! Trample all!
（オークたち）
蹂躙せよ！　蹂躙せよ！
蹂躙せよ！　蹂躙せよ…
The Orc army filled the marshlands.
（リムル）
湿地帯を埋め尽くすオークの大軍
From one corner of their ranks,
a commotion arose.
その一角から ざわめきが生じた
There is no need to fear these
pigs any more than before!
（ガビル）
豚どもを
必要以上に恐れることなどない！
湿地帯は我らの領域！
These marshlands are our domain!
素早い動きで
オークどもを攪乱(かくらん)するのだ！
We will throw the Orcs into
confusion with our agility!
We will not lose to these dimwits
whose feet are held by the mud!
ぬかるみに足を取られるノロマに
遅れは取らん！
All right!
（部下たち）
やった〜！
攻撃が効いてるぜ！
Our attack is making a dent!
Indeed.
しかり！
Mere Orcs are no match for us Lizardmen!
（ガビル）
オークなど
我らリザードマンの敵ではない
Right! Withdraw for now!
よし　一旦 離脱！
Gabiru's men had to acknowledge his talents.
（リムル）
ガビルの実力は
仲間たちが認めるものだった
What's happening?
（ガビル）何だ？
If there was anything
they didn't account for,
（リムル）
ただ １つ誤算があるとすれば
ガビルは知らなかった
it was that Gabiru didn't know...
the terror of the Orc Lord.
オークロードの恐怖を…
The Orcs... are eating other Orcs?
オークが… オークを食っている！
The chieftain did know the
terror of the Orc Lord.
（リムル）
首領は知っていた
オークロードの恐怖を…
This difference between
the two of them was now
その違いが今 結果となって
ガビルに牙をむく
bearing its fangs at Gabiru.
（オークたち）
蹂躙せよ！　蹂躙せよ！
蹂躙せよ！
Trample all! Trample all! Trample all!
The strength of this comrade
we eat is now ours!
食べた仲間の力を我が物に！
The strength of this prey we eat is now ours!
食べた獲物の力を我が物に！
Next time, "The Great Clash."
（大賢者）
次回「大激突」
The Great Clash